Register of the Harold S. Matthews Papers, 1936-1968
Hoover Institution Archives
Harold S. Matthews Papers,
1936-1968
70051
Matthews, Harold S. (Harold Shepard)
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, reports, and printed matter, relating to Christian missionary work in China and Japan, and to the communist movement in China.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions.; Christianity--China.; Communism.; Communism--China.; Missions--China.; Missions--Japan.; China.; Japan.; United States--Foreign relations.; Missionaries.
Biographical Note
1894 Born, Hull, Iowa
1916 B.A., Grinnell College (Iowa)
1920 M.A., University of Chicago
1930 B.D., Chicago Theological Seminary
1922-1942 Missionary for American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, North China Mission
1944-1953 Secretary, American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, Boston Headquarters
Container List
- Biographical file (Box 1)
- Boston Study Conference on China, Post-War Planning, 1944
- Clippings
- Communism in China
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous
- Foreign Missions Conference of North America - Centrality of the Church in China, 1945
- Foreign Missions file. Includes reports, memoranda, newsletters, lists, and other material concerning the activities in China and Japan of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
  - 1936-1949
  - 1950-1968 (Box 2)
  - Undated
- Printed matter (Box 3)
- Study of the Missionary Obligation sponsored by the International Missionary Council, 1952
- Writings of Harold S. Matthews
  - "Four Chinese Christian Heroes"
  - "Lessons to Be Learned from Experiences of Christian Missions in China"
  - "Mid-Fukien Synod of the Church of Christ in China"
  - "Missionary Situation in China," 1952
  - "Our Mission in China"
  - "The Story of the North China Mission of the American Board, 1935-1960"
  - "Three Loyal Chinese Church Leaders"